

# Stephen Swanson

Web | Software Developer

#### **Details**

Helsinki, Finland +358 406757425 swanson.stephen.h@gmail.com

#### Links

Portolio https://www.swansondev.me/

GitHub https://github.com/YB-BigSwan

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/ stephen-swanson-h/

## Programming Languages

JavaScript • TypeScript • Java • Python • SQL • HTML • CSS

### **Technologies**

React • Next • Express • Node •
React Native • Spring (Maven) •
MySQL • MariaDB • MongoDB •
Leaflet • Git • GitHub Actions CI/CD •
GitLab Ci/CD • Material UI • Tailwind
CSS

#### Skills

Teamwork • Communication •
Problem-solving • Adaptability •
Creativity • Critical thinking

## Languages

English (Native)
Finnish (B2)

#### **Hobbies**

Gaming • Playing/making music •
Cycling • Hiking • Cooking

## **Professional Summary**

Third year Business Information Technology student majoring in software development with more than 2 years of project working experience. Experienced in developing websites, as well as testing and debugging. Excels in optimizing user experience and creating responsive and accessible web applications. I am currently seeking a trainee or junior position as I change careers.

## **Work Experience**

Career Transition, Helsinki, FI • Software Developer (12/2019 - present)

Relocating to Finland prompted a deliberate career shift, driving me to acquire a B2 Finnish language certification and pursue a BBA in Business Information Technology, specializing in software development. With graduation nearing, I am actively seeking a trainee or junior level position in web or software development to kickstart my new career.

- Attained B2 certification in Finnish language, contributing to effective communication in a professional Finnish environment.
- Enrolled in a BBA of Business Information Technology, majoring in software development, set to graduate by the end of 2024.
- Engaged in 2.5 years of dedicated learning and project work to proactively gain hands-on experience and skill mastery, strategically positioning myself for entry into the software development field.

Men's Warehouse, Salt Lake City, UT, USA • Sales Associate (01/2019 – 10/2019)

- Proactively assessed and adapted to customer preferences to guide sales efforts.
- Established and meticulously maintained customer accounts, ensuring personalized service, and fostering long-term relationships.

Rite of Passage RTC, Logan, UT, USA • Therapeutic Mentor (01/2018 – 10/2019)

- Orchestrated comprehensive training sessions for staff, ensuring a high level of competence and proficiency in CPR, First Aid, and Safe Crisis Management.
- Efficiently collected and organized data gathered by mentors, contributing to comprehensive reporting.

#### **Education and Certifications**

Haaga-Helia UAS, Helsinki, FI • BBA Business Information Technology (2022- Dec 2024)

Finnish Integration Program, Helsinki, Finland • B2 Finnish Language certification (2021)

Utah State University, Logan, UT, USA • BS Psychology (2018)

#### **Volunteer Work**

Satakuntalainen Osakunta, Helsinki, FI • Web Administrator (01/2024 – present)

- Played a key role in maintaining the legacy website and overseeing Telegram/
   Email bots to ensure effective online communication.
- Led the development of a new, modern, and responsive website for the organization, contributing to an enhanced online presence.

#### **Professional Reference**

Juhani Välimäki • Haaga-Helia • Teacher • Application Development, Databases, Design

Mobile: +358 40 488 7307

Email: juhani.valimaki@haaga-helia.fi